[{"qid": 5, "question": "Retrieve employees who are working on a specific project (e.g., Project A):", "answer": "SELECT * FROM Employees WHERE proj_id = (SELECT proj_id FROM Projects WHERE proj_name = 'Project A');", "tbl_structure": ["Employees", "Departments"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 6, "question": "Retrieve employees whose age is greater than 30:", "answer": "SELECT * FROM Employees WHERE emp_age > 30;", "tbl_structure": ["Employees"], "cand_ans": "incorrect"}, {"qid": 3, "question": "Retrieve all Project records:", "answer": "SELECT * FROM Projects;", "tbl_structure": ["Projects"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 10, "question": "Retrieve the number of employees in each department:", "answer": "SELECT d.dept_name, COUNT(e.emp_id) AS num_employees FROM Departments d LEFT JOIN Employees e ON d.dept_id = e.dept_id GROUP BY d.dept_name;", "tbl_structure": ["Departments", "Employees"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 14, "question": "Retrieve the employees whose names start with the letter 'J':", "answer": "SELECT * FROM Employees WHERE emp_name LIKE 'J%';", "tbl_structure": ["Employees"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 7, "question": "Retrieve employees whose salary is between 40,000 and 60,000:", "answer": "SELECT * FROM Employees WHERE emp_salary BETWEEN 40000.00 AND 60000.00;", "tbl_structure": ["Employees"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 11, "question": "Retrieve the total salary expenditure for each department:", "answer": "SELECT d.dept_name, SUM(e.emp_salary) AS total_salary FROM Departments d LEFT JOIN Employees e ON d.dept_id = e.dept_id GROUP BY d.dept_name;", "tbl_structure": ["Departments", "Employees"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 19, "question": "Retrieve the departments with no employees:", "answer": "SELECT d.* FROM Departments d LEFT JOIN Employees e ON d.dept_id = e.dept_id WHERE e.emp_id IS NULL;", "tbl_structure": ["Employees", "Departments"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 1, "question": "Retrieve all employee records:", "answer": "SELECT * FROM Employees;", "tbl_structure": ["Employees"], "cand_ans": ""}, {"qid": 15, "question": "Retrieve the department with the highest number of employees:", "answer": "SELECT d.dept_name, COUNT(e.emp_id) AS num_employees FROM Departments d LEFT JOIN Employees e ON d.dept_id = e.dept_id GROUP BY d.dept_name ORDER BY num_employees DESC LIMIT 1;", "tbl_structure": ["Employees", "Departments"], "cand_ans": ""}]